Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and we
have a very fun lesson for you today.
That's right. We're going to talk about toys.
So we're going to actually take a look at a
lot of different types of toys and we're going
to be listening to a couple of commercials.
That's right. So we've got two
children who are watching TV
and they're listening to a
number of different commercials.
So we're going to learn about
some of these very popular
products in a moment. Let's
first listen to our dialogue.
Make large colorful gems for you and your
friends with five special molds. Comes with
a new sparkling bright Playdow compound in
four new colors. Treasure chest ultimately.
Wow, mommy can I get that for my birthday?
Hi, g-grain, rogue and Professor X.
Collect all four of these special edition
collectible X-Men action figures and decide
the future of the mutants in our world.
No way! I want Professor X!
The new collector's edition
nursery rhymes, porcelain dolls.
Little Bo Peep comes with
their own sheep and staff.
Her clothes are made with the
finest fabrics and real Italian lace
and her face has been hand
painted by our finest artists. Only $199.
Oh, she's pretty! I've never
had a porcelain doll before.
I doubt mom and dad will
get you that for your birthday.
She costs a pretty penny.
Plus, you'd most likely break her.
What is better than the
board? What is better
than one board day?
Three board games in one!
Enjoy playing chess and
checkers on the side of the board.
But if you're looking
for some more fun, plug
that, and play the
classic game of sorry.
Fits and genius!
Why hasn't anyone thought of that before?
Now you can take Spongebob
Squarepants wherever you go
with the new Spongebob
Squarepants glow in the dark yo-yo.
And now, back to our show.
Alright, we're back. So a
lot of great toys and actually,
it's very popular that while
maybe you're watching cartoons,
you get a lot of these commercials
that are selling you all types of toys.
Absolutely, because
normally children watch
cartoons and children
like toys, so it makes sense.
Exactly. So why don't
we take a look at six
keywords that we have for
you on language takeaway?
Okay, Marco. So what's the first
word we're looking at here today?
Alright, we have actually a brand, a very
famous type of toy. They're called Legos.
Legos. So Legos are basically little pieces
that you put together to build things.
Yeah, they're like little blocks.
Okay, so when you see them,
they don't look like anything.
But as a child, you get to
create anything you want.
So Legos have become very famous.
They have like special types that
you can recreate, maybe a
spaceship from Star Wars, a pirate ship.
A lot of different types now.
Okay, so the one in
today's commercial is
pirate Legos, so they're
building a pirate ship.
Exactly. Legos. Alright.
And the next toy that we
have is also a proper noun.
It's a brand and
it's called Play-Doh.
Play-Doh.
Okay, so play like playing
with something, playing
basketball, but Play-Doh
is, it's like clay, right?
It's like clay, but it's
made out of flower, I
think, and you can shape
it into anything you want.
So when I was a little, I used
to make Play-Doh animals.
You know, you could make
a ball and you make another
ball and then all of a
sudden you have a cow.
Right, so it's a very soft texture
type of a material that you can mold,
you can give it different shapes,
and that's what we call Play-Doh.
And obviously, as you say, it's safe for
children, I think it's made out of some flower,
some flowers, and I think a lot of children
sometimes eat this, so it's pretty safe for kids.
Right, so yeah, that's Play-Doh. It's
a proper noun, and I guess everyone
just calls it Play-Doh, so this is
the toy that we're talking about.
Now, moving on that we are talking
about the X-Men, Wolverine, G-G-A, Rogue,
Professor X, and all of these come in
little statues that we call action figures.
Alright, so what you're talking about
here are obviously the X-Men, Marco.
And X-Men, there are many different kinds of X-Men you
have, like you said, Wolverine, who's maybe one of the most
famous and rogue, but when you collect these little
statues, these little dolls, they're called action figures.
So figure is like a kind of doll.
Right, so the X-Men is just an
example, you have action figures of all
sorts of cartoons or movies, Star
Wars action figures are very popular.
Right, or GI Joe action
figures are very popular as well.
That's right, so they're little toy
statues that children play with.
Alright, moving on now we have an
adjective, a way to describe the X-Men.
That's right, so the
X-Men as you know are
not normal people,
they have special powers.
Some X-Men can fly, Wolverine has animal
abilities, he can use his long claws.
So these are mutants, that means
that they were humans, but something
changed in them and it makes
them have these special powers.
So a mutant is maybe a
person that has special powers,
like as you say, Wolverine
and all these types of X-Men,
but I guess taking
maybe a look at the verb
mutate, that means to
change, to change, right?
Okay, so to mutate is to change, so
we could say, I found a frog that had
three legs, so it clearly mutated,
because normally frogs have like four legs.
Exactly, you see that
sometimes with chickens
that maybe have two
heads or something like this.
These are mutants, they have mutated.
Okay, very good.
And now moving on
to our dolls, they were
talking about these
beautiful porcelain dolls.
Okay, so let's talk about porcelain,
because I think everyone knows
what a doll is, but porcelain
is a special kind of doll, right?
Right, it's a material.
Usually you can find this material
very commonly in your plates.
It's not clear, it's not glass.
No.
It's colored, it's normally whitish,
and very, very fine, very pretty.
So you call it porcelain, I guess
it's a type of ceramic, right?
That's right.
Okay, so yeah, you have
porcelain dolls, many people also
have very fine china that
you call it, like dinner plates,
or teacup, or teacups, and those
are usually made of porcelain.
All right, and finally they were
talking about a game that has
three games in one, and one of
the kids said, wow, that's ingenious.
In genius, this is a great
word, makes you sound
really fluent, so ingenious
basically means clever.
Right, it's a really good idea.
It's a very clever, good idea, yeah.
So if something is ingenious,
it's just wow, it's very creative.
For example, I have a pair
of gloves, but on the fingers,
sometimes I can pull a cover over
them, and they turn into mittens.
Right, I think it's ingenious, because I
have gloves and mittens all the time.
All right, so a lot of interesting
words there, a lot of specific
toys, and particularly brands
that you may or may not know.
But why don't we go back
and listen to the dialogue
again, and we'll be
back with Fluency Builder.
SpongeBob SquarePans will be
right back after these brief messages.
What's that on the horizon?
A pirate ship, raid
villages, and find buried
treasure with these
new pirates' Lego set.
Build the ship and
decide who rules the sea.
Cool!
The new Play-Doh Sparkling
Brights precious gempress.
Make large, colorful gems for you
and your friends with five special molds.
Those with the new Sparkling Brights
Play-Doh compound in four new colors.
Treasure chests sold separately.
Wow, mommy, can I get that for my birthday?
Wolverine, Jean Grey,
Rogue, and Professor X.
Collect all four of these
special edition collectible X-Men
action figures and decide the
future of the mutants in our world.
No way! I want Professor X!
The new Collector's Edition
Nursery Rhymes, Porcelain Dolls.
Little Bo Peep comes with
their own sheep and staff.
Her clothes are made with
the finest fabrics and real Italian
lace, and her face has been
hand-painted by our finest artists.
Only $199.
Oh, she's pretty!
I've never had a porcelain doll before.
I doubt mom and dad will
get you that for your birthday.
She costs a pretty penny.
Plus, you'd most likely break her.
What is better than a board?
What is better than one board game?
Three board games in one.
Enjoy playing chess and
checkers on this side of the board.
But if you're looking
for some more fun,
flip it and play the
classic game of "Sorry."
That's ingenious!
Why hasn't anyone thought of that before?
Now, you can take SpongeBob
SquarePants wherever you go with
the new SpongeBob SquarePants
go low in their dark yo-yo.
And now, back to our show!
Okay, so the first phrase here in fluency
builders, a really important one for anyone who's
buying anything because you often see this
phrase on packages or you hear it in commercials.
Right.
As you saw in the Play-Doh commercial, the
guy said treasure chest sold separately.
Okay, sold separately.
That means the treasure
chest is not included.
You have to buy it extra.
As you say, you usually see it in
packaging as well, maybe you buy a toy car.
And at the bottom, it will
say batteries sold separately.
That means there are
no batteries in the box.
You have to buy batteries extra.
Exactly.
So that's what the phrase
sold separately means.
It indicates that it's not included
in the product that you are buying.
All right, now moving on again
to the action figures and the
dolls, we saw this very
interesting way of describing them.
For example, the action figure said special
edition collectible X-Men action figures.
Okay, special edition.
This is really important.
And it's very common,
I think, with special
toys or action figures
or even baseball cards.
Special edition means that they're produced
specially on one occasion at one time.
They're not always produced.
Right.
So for example, if you have, like you say,
baseball cards or maybe action figures.
They're produced normally,
but then a limited amount, a
special type of the same
action figure will be produced.
So that's a special edition or also
commonly known as a collector's edition.
All right.
So some people collect stamps, you
know, stamps for letters that you send.
And I know many
countries like America offer
special edition or
collector's edition stamps.
These are produced once and
usually they mark a special occasion.
Like the Olympics in 1996,
we had special edition stamps.
Right.
So these special edition
objects are usually not used.
They're for collectors, like the
name says, right, collector's edition.
Right.
So you plan to sell them later
on or you collect them for yourself.
They're not normal.
Right.
They usually go up in value
because they're very limited.
That's right.
Okay.
So collector's edition special edition.
And now when they were
talking about the porcelain
dolls, as well, it's
pretty expensive, right?
Almost $200.
That's a really expensive doll.
And so one of the kids said, you know what?
I think mom and dad won't buy you
that because it costs a pretty penny.
A pretty penny.
This does not mean that
the penny is beautiful.
Right.
A penny is a one cent
coin in the United States.
That means it's very, very low in value.
The coin.
But a pretty penny is
actually the opposite.
It means it's very expensive.
So how would you use
this in another example?
I've always wanted to buy a Ferrari,
but man, Ferrari's cost a pretty penny.
Okay.
So you have to add the word cost
before you say pretty penny, right?
That's right.
You can't say it is a pretty penny.
You have to say it costs a pretty penny.
Or it's worth a pretty penny.
Exactly.
It's worth a pretty penny.
Okay.
Very good.
And for our last phrase, I think
this one is a very good phrase.
Because it describes
a lot of different toys
that glow in the dark,
glow in the dark toys.
Okay.
So something that glows in the
dark, the verb here is too glow.
It means that it can be
seen even when it's dark.
Right.
So for example, when I turn
the lights off and I can see
this yoyo in my room, that
means it's glow in the dark.
It has light even in the dark.
Right.
So there are a lot of
different toys and things
like this, usually
glow in the dark toys.
They have a green glow.
Right.
They look green in the dark.
I used to have stars.
So they were stickers, stars, stickers.
And I put them on my ceiling so that
when I was in bed, I could look at them.
And they were glow in the dark.
So when the lights
were off, I still had stars.
You can still see them.
Right.
So yeah, glow in the dark.
It's a way of describing an item, an object
that you are able to see in the dark.
All right, so that's all we
have for you on language.
have for you on fluency builder.
When we go back, listen
to the dialogue one last time.
And we'll be back to talk some more.
We are cool.
The new Play-Doh Sparkling
Brights Precious Gym Press.
Make large colorful gems for you
and your friends with five special molds.
Comes with the new Sparkling Brights
Play-Doh compound in four new colors.
Treasure Chest holds up really.
Wow, Bonnie.
Can I get that for my birthday?
All right, gee, great.
Rogue and Professor X.
Collect all four of
these special edition
collectible X-Men action figures and decide
the future of the mutants in our world.
No way.
I want Professor X.
The new collector's edition
nursery rhymes porcelain dolls.
Little BoBabe comes with
their own sheep and staff.
Her clothes are made with the
finest fabrics and real Italian lace.
And her face has been hand
painted by our finest artists.
Only $199.
Oh, she's pretty.
I've never had a porcelain doll before.
I doubt mom and dad will
get you that for your birthday.
She costs a pretty penny.
Plus, you'd most likely break.
One is better than a board.
One is better than one board game.
Three board games in one.
Enjoy playing chest and
checkers on the side of the board.
But if you're looking for some more
fun, then play the classic game of Surrey.
Fits and genius.
Why hasn't anyone thought of that before?
Now you can take Spongebob
Squarepants wherever you go
with the new Spongebob
Squarepants Glow in the dark yo-yo.
And now, back to our show.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, so talking about toys.
These are really interesting toys.
Are there any specific
toys that you had when you
were growing up or that
you really, really liked?
I had an amazing Brio train set.
OK.
This is when I was young.
And a train set is basically
like Legos with trains.
So you build a track.
And you push the train around the track.
And so I used to have a track
that was as big as the living room.
And my challenge, my goal
was to use every single piece.
Wow.
Which is very hard because some
pieces don't fit with other pieces.
And so that was my favorite toy
because I got to be very creative.
And then you would turn on the train.
It would go away.
It wasn't electric.
I wasn't.
So I had to push it myself.
OK.
What was your favorite toy?
Actually, when I was growing
up, I used to collect little toy cars.
I had a lot of toys.
Surprise.
I used to have a lot of little toy cars.
And I even had a little special, I don't
know, like a box for them when you can.
So I could see them.
And then as time went on, I
got to collect the scale cars.
You know, the ones that
are one to 10, one to four.
Did you build them or did you buy them?
No, usually I bought them made.
I actually tried the whole building model
cars, model airplanes, but it's so hard.
Very hard.
Even adults have a hard time.
It's very difficult.
I don't know what type of kid actually
does that when they're growing up.
But yeah, so many toys out there.
So many people collect
them, play with them.
You have childhood toys
that you're very fond of.
So that's what we want to know.
What type of toy did you grow up with?
What did you like to play
with when you were a kid?
Or if you have kids, what
toys do your kids like?
Because we're not too
familiar with toys these days.
We'd be curious to hear about those.
That's right.
I want to hear from you.
Come to EnglishPod.com.
And we'll see everyone there.
Bye.